신사 숙녀 여러분
절 따라오시면
Ladies and gentlemen,
if you follow me,
이다음 방이 아주 흥미롭다는 걸
알게 되실 겁니다
I think you would find
this next room very interested.
여러분도 조사해 보면 아시겠지만...
You can do what you get to canvass but...
이것들은 세계적으로 유명한
크롬웰 가의 전시품입니다
this is the world famous
Cromwell family exhibit.
매번 이 방으로 걸어 들어갈 때마다
저는 아직도 소름이 돋는답니다
I still get goosebumps
everytime I walk into this room.
유럽에서 가장 방대한
개인 소장품이거든요
It is the largest private collection
in Europe.
크롬웰 가 사람들은
가구, 그림에서
The Cromwell family has
collected everything
중세 무기류까지 모든 것들을
수집해 왔습니다
from furniture and paintings
to medieval weaponry.
그리고 이것은... 소장품 중
단연 왕좌를 차지한 물품이죠
This, of course, is
the crown jewel of the exhibit.
말장난이 아니라 진짜입니다
No pun intended.
알렉산더 다이아몬드입니다
The Alexander diamond.
엘리자베스 여왕의 대관식 때
쓰인 것이죠
It was worn by queen Elizabeth
at her coronation.
전문가들은 이걸 세상에서
가장 완벽한 다이아몬드라 부릅니다
Experts have called it the most
perfect diamond in the world.
이게 얼마의 가치가
있는지 궁금하시겠죠
You're probably wondering
what it's worth.
사실, 아무도 모른답니다
하지만 이건 말씀드릴 수 있겠군요
Actually, no one knows.
But I can tell you this.
이 작은 보석은 런던 로이즈 사에
2천만 달러의 보험이 들어 있습니다
That little rock has been insured by
Lloyd's of London for $20 million.
MONK Season 4 Epi. 13
Mr. Monk and the Big Reward
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
딕테이션
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
싱크편집
최자앵(ashaa@nate.com)
한글번역
신성아(elley@nate.com)
번역수정
홍관호(kwanho_hong@nate.com)
한글교정
임재영(dreamimage@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2006/02/03
- 42달러 80센트입니다
- 네. 여기 있어요
- That's $42.80.
- Okay, there we go.
쿠폰도 있어요
And I have a coupon.
이건 사용하실 수 없네요
기한이 어제까지거든요
I can't take this,
it expired yesterday.
어제요? 이런, 그렇군요
Yesterday?
Oh, she's right.
난 가끔 타임머신이
있었으면 한답니다
Darn. Sometimes I wish
I had a time machine.
그러니까, 타임머신이 있었다면
Wait, if you had a time machine,
표백제를 50센트 싸게 사는 데
사용했을 거란 말씀이세요?
you would use it to go back
to save 50 cents on lysol?
네, 맞아요. 그거죠
Yes. Yes, I would.
에이브러햄 링컨을 구하는 데
사용하는 게 아니라요?
You wouldn't use it
to save Abraham Lincoln?
알았어요. 링컨을 구하면 되잖아요
당신과는 끝도 없군요
Fine, I'll save Lincoln.
It never ends with you.
손님, 다른 카드는 없나요?
이건 승인 거부라고 나오는데요
Sir, do you have a different card?
It says declined.
승인 거부라고요?
Declined?
몽크 씨, 은행에 돈이 있긴 한가요?
Mr. Monk, do you have
any money in the bank?
아뇨 / 그러시겠죠. 알았어요
No. / That could be it.
Okay.
죄송합니다. 서둘러요
I'm sorry.
Please hurry.
알았어요. 저한테...
34달러 있네요 / 그게 다예요?
All right, I've got...
$34. / Is that it?
어제가 월급날이었잖아요
Yesterday was payday.
네, 그랬죠
그런데 전 못 받았잖아요
Yes, it was.
But I didn't get paid.
점점 이름뿐인 월급날이
되어가고 있다고요
You know, your paydays are
becoming sort of theoretical.
- 어서요. 물건 몇 개 빼세요
- 그건 안 돼요
Come on, you need to put
some stuff back. / No, I can't.
그게, 내가...
Look, I, I...
목록을 작성했거든요. 여기 있는 것
모두 그 목록에 있는 거예요
I made a list.
Everything here is on the list.
알아요, 안다고요
다시 사러 오면 돼요
I know, I know. We're gonna
come back later and pick it up.
- 어서요. 사람들이 기다리잖아요
- 알았어요
- Come on, people are waiting.
- Okay.
어... 그럼 이거. 잠깐, 안 돼요
이건 필요하거든요
Uh, this then. Oh, wait, no.
I need this.
이건... 이 스프레이도 필요해요
Oh, this.
Gotta have this spray.
좋아요. 이건 어때요?
이것들 중 한 개 골라요
All right, how about...
how about one of these?
그래요. 이걸로 하죠
아니, 아뇨. 음... 아니에요
Yeah, this one.
No, no. Um, no.
그걸로 해요. 아, 잠깐만
Let's go with that one. All right.
Oh, wait a second.
이봐요, 빨리해요!
Come on, hurry up!
두 명의 자식 중 하나만 선택하는
심정이네요. 그게 수프라는 것만 빼면
It's like Sophie's choice.
Except it's soup.
알았어요. 수프는 놔두죠
Okay, we're keeping the soup.
이거, 이거, 이거
그리고 이거 빼 주세요
Putting back this, this, this, and this.
몽크 씨, 우리 꼴을 봐요
둘 다 빈털터리라니, 말도 안 돼요
Mr. Monk, look at us.
This is ridiculous. We're both broke.
3주 동안 새로운 사건도
못 맡았잖아요
We haven't had a new case
in three weeks.
내가 어떻게 하면 좋겠어요?
What do you want me to do?
수임료를 올려야죠
경감님께 말씀해 보세요
You need to get a raise.
You gotta talk to the captain.
계속 이럴 수는 없잖아요
We can't go on like this.
난 돈을 더 달라고 얘기하는 건
잘 못하는 사람이에요
I'm not good at this,
asking for more money.
좋아요. 그럼 제가 하게 해 주세요
Okay, then let me do the talking.
- 그것도 안 되겠네요
- 몽크 씨는 더 받을 자격이 있어요
- I'm not good at that either.
- Mr. Monk, you deserve a raise.
경찰들을 위해 혼자 힘으로
큰 사건들을 많이 해결하셨잖아요
You've solved a lot of big cases
for them single-handedly.
- 조금 도와준 것뿐일 수도 있죠
- 아니, 아니, 아니라니까요
- Maybe I helped a little.
- No, no, no, no.
그렇게 생각하시면 안 되죠
You can't think like that.
자신을 자랑스러워 하셔야 해요
좀 떠벌리기도 하셔야죠
You gotta brag about yourself.
You gotta toot your own horn.
난 떠버리와는 거리가 멀어요
I'm not much of a tooter.
떠벌리는 법도 좀 배워 두세요
You better learn how to toot.
- '떠벌리다'란 단어 재밌네요
- 퍽도 재밌겠네요
- Toot's a funny word.
- Hilarious.
안녕하세요, 글래디스
Oh, hello. Gladys.
이쪽은 나탈리 티거, 여긴 글래디스예요
아주 멋진 분이죠
Natalie Teeger, this is Gladys.
Gladys is great.
글래디스는 몇 년 동안 여길
깨끗이 청소해 주고 계세요
Gladys has been cleaning up
around here for years.
남는 시간에 제가
글래디스를 도와주곤 했죠
I used to help her out
in my spare time.
- 아, 정말 그랬죠. 기억나시죠?
- 그래요
- Oh, boy. Oh, boy. Remember?
- Yeah.
내가 금지 명령을 받아냈을
때까지는 그랬죠. 기억나겠죠?
Until I got that restraining order.
Remember?
좋은 시절이었죠. 좋은 시절...
Good times. Good times.
책상 밑면도 청소하셔야 해요
글래디스, 밑면도 하실 거죠?
You have to get underneath, right,
Gladys? Under?
왜요? 아무도 거긴
살펴보지 않는다고요
Why?
Nobody ever looks there.
하지만 당신만은 알잖아요
그것 자체로 보상이 아닐까요?
But you'll know it's clean.
Isn't that its own reward? You'll know.
경감님 말씀이 그쪽이랑 말할
필요가 없다고 하시더군요
The captain says I don't
have to talk to you.
알아요. 하지만 밑면요, 네?
책상 밑면도 꼭 하세요
I know, I know. But under, okay?
Under the table.
저도 도와 드리고 싶어요
정말입니다
I wanna help you guys, okay?
I really do.
벌써 4번이나 똑같은
질문을 들었다고요
They already questioned me four times.
랜디스 씨에게만 그런 것은 아닙니다
It's not just you, Mr. Landis.
경비원 분들과 청소부들
We're talking to all the guards,
the cleaning staff,
큐레이터들, 박물관에 있던
모든 사람들과 얘기하고 있어요
curators, anybody who was
at the museum.
그렇겠죠. 하지만 전 아직
집에 가지도 못했다고요
Yeah, but I haven't even
been home yet.
그리고 협조에 감사드립니다
And I appreciate that.
공식 진술만 끝내면
가셔도 좋습니다
We just need your official statement,
then you're free to go.
기록을 위해서 묻겠는데
도난 당시 어디에 계셨죠?
So for the record,
where were you during the robbery?
다섯 번째 같은 질문이군요
For the fifth time, okay?
전 본 층의 제 구역에 있었고
결코 벗어난 적이 없습니다
I was at my station on the main floor.
I never left.
- 화장실도 가지 않았다니까요
- 평소와 다른 소리를 듣진 않으셨나요?
- I didn't even go to the bathroom.
- And you didn't hear anything unusual?
아뇨. 전 도난 장소에서
3층이나 떨어진 곳에 있었다고요
No, sir.
I was three floors away.
알겠습니다
Okay.
잠시만 실례하겠습니다
뭐 마실 거라도 드릴까요? / 아뇨
Excuse me for a second.
Can I get you something to drink? / No.
- 몽크 씨, 나탈리 씨 / 무슨 일이야?
- 아직 못 들으셨어요?
- Monk, Nat. / What's going on?
- Oh, you haven't heard?
맥밀런 박물관의 절도 사건이에요
아주 큰 건이죠
Robbery at the MacMillan museum.
It was big big.
- 알렉산더 다이아몬드예요
- 우와
- The Alexander diamond.
- Whoa.
놀랄 만하죠. 절도과에서
수사를 도와달래서
I know whoa.
Robbery division asked us to help out,
그곳에 있던 모든 사람들의
진술을 받는 중입니다
so we're taking statements
from everybody on site.
그럼 저 사람을 마약 관련 죄로
체포하진 않겠군
So you're not arresting him
about the drugs.
어... 네. 무슨 마약요?
Uh, no. What drugs?
저 사람 손톱이 더럽잖아
적갈색 인(燐)처럼 보이는데
His fingertips are stained.
Looks like red phosphorous.
'크리스털 메쓰'를 만들 때 쓰지
어딘가에 작업실이 있을 거야
You get that from making crystal meth.
He's gotta have a lab somewhere.
알았어요. 확인해 볼게요
Okay, I'll check it out.
저기, 랜디스 씨
이쪽으로 와 주시겠어요?
Excuse me, Mr. Landis.
Could you come here, please?
경감님이 절 찾으시면
B 취조실에 있다고 전해 주세요
If the captain needs me,
I'll be in interrogation room B.
이쪽으로 가시죠
Uh, right this way.
- 왜요?
- 몰라서 물으세요?
- What?
- You know what.
방금 공짜로 사건을
해결해 주셨잖아요
You just solved that case for free.
그럼 어떻게 했어야 했는데요?
What was I supposed to do?
만약 아이스크림을 팔고 있었다면
공짜로 막 퍼 주시겠네요?
Well, if you're selling ice cream,
would you hand out free scoops?
그럼 뭐라고 말했어야 하는데요?
What was I supposed to say?
"이봐, 경위. 이 방 어딘가에
마약 판매상이 있네"
Hey, lieutenant, there's a drug dealer
somewhere in this room.
- "20달러 주면 누군지 알려 주지"라고요?
- 그럼 최소한 20달러는 벌겠죠
- I'll tell you who it is for $20.
- At least we'd have $20.
좋아요. 저기 경감님이 계시네요
All right, there's the captain.
명심하세요. 몸값을 높이세요
몽크 씨는 자격이 있어요!
Remember, you deserve a raise.
You deserve it!
알았어요. 나탈리가 그렇다면
그 말이 맞겠죠
Okay, when you're right,
you're right.
저기, 경감님? / 몽크 왔나
여기엔 무슨 일이야?
Okay, captain? / Hey, monk.
What are you doing here?
- 경감님, 말씀드릴 게 있어요
- 잠시만 기다리겠나?
Captain, I have to talk to you
about something. / Can it wait?
알았어요. 다시 올게요
Okay. Well, we'll come back.
자, 다시 왔군요
Okay, we're back.
그게... 나탈리?
And...
Natalie?
경감님... / 돈 얘기라면 잊게나
우리도 거지 신세야
Captain... / If this is about money,
forget about it. We're broke.
경찰서에 땡전 한 푼도 없다네
방금 또 고용 동결 명령서를 받았어
The department is strapped.
We just got another hiring freeze.
경감님, 새로운 사건을
못 맡은 지 3주나 됐어요
Captain, we haven't had
a new case in three weeks.
나탈리 말이 맞습니다. 오랫동안
큰 살인 사건이 없었어요
You know, you're right. There hasn't
been a major homicide in a long time.
그래도 희망을 품게나
낙관적으로 생각하게
But you gotta keep your hopes up.
Stay optimistic.
알았어요. 고맙습니다
Okay, well, thank you very much.
경감님, 왜 이러세요. 그냥
앉아서 전화만 기다릴 순 없어요
Okay, captain, come on, we can't just
sit around waiting for the phone to ring.
그건 공평치 않아요
우리도 뭔가 기댈 게 있어야죠
It's not fair to us.
We have no security.
내가 어떻게 하길 바라는 겁니까?
What do you want me to do?
- 정식 자문으로 채용해 주세요
- 뭐라고요?
- We wanna be put on retainer.
- What?
변호사 같은 자문으로요
최소한의 고정 소득이 필요하다고요
Yeah, retainer like a lawyer.
We want a guaranteed income.
많이도 필요 없어요. 약간의
안전장치가 필요한 것뿐이죠 / 맞아요
Look, it doesn't have to be much.
We just need a little security. / Yes.
알았어요. 가능한지 알아보죠
하지만 큰 기대는 말아요. 알았죠?
Okay, I'll see what I can do.
But don't get your hopes up, okay?
다른 건?
Anything else?
글래디스 말인데요
It's about Gladys.
- 글래디스와 얘기했어?
- 경감님...
- Have you been talking to Gladys?
- Captain...
글래디스와 얘기하지 말라고 했을 텐데
I told you not to talk to Gladys.
또 책상 밑면을 청소하지 않잖아요
She's not cleaning under the tables again.
경감님이 글래디스와
얘기해 보셔야 할 것 같아요
I think you should talk to her.
그럴 거야
누구한테 던졌는지 물어보지
I will. About her aim.
아래층으로 데려가요
Get him downstairs.
몽크 씨 말씀이 맞았어요
You were right.
취조실로 데려갔는데
I get this guy in the room,
모든 걸 다 부정하더군요
안절부절 못하고 불안해 했어요
he's denying everything.
He's twitching, he's nervous.
수색 영장을 받아내서
집을 샅샅이 뒤지겠다고 협박했죠
I threaten to get a search warrant
and tear his house apart.
전화기를 들고 번호를 누르려고 하니까
그놈이 포기하더라고요
I pick up the phone,
I start to dial, he collapses.
완전히 포기했어요
마약 제조실은 지하실에 있대요
He gave it all up.
Crystal meth lab in his basement.
마약 담당과에서 그쪽으로 가고 있어요
Narcotics is on their way over.
- 신세 졌네요
- 잘됐군
- I owe you one.
- Okay.
- 왜요?
- 아시잖아요
- What?
- You know what.
아, 그거요?
Oh, the thing?
- 아이스크림 퍼 주는 거요?
- 맞아요
- About the ice cream and the free scoops?
- That's right.
몽크 씨?
Mr. Monk?
- 우린 부자예요. 큰 건을 잡았어요
- 아, 잘됐군요
- We're rich. We hit the jackpot.
- Oh, good.
보세요. 알렉산더 다이아몬드에
관한 건데요
Look, it's about the Alexander diamond.
런던 로이즈에서 그걸 찾는 사람에게
100만 달러를 보상하겠대요
Lloyd's of London is offering a $1 million
reward to anybody that finds it.
- 아무것도 묻지 않고요
- 그래서요?
- No questions asked.
- So?
몽크 씨는 그 다이아몬드를
찾아낼 수 있잖아요
Mr. Monk, you can find that diamond.
아닌 거 같은데요
Ah, I don't think so.
뭐라고요?
몽크 씨는 훌륭한 수사관이에요
What?
You're a great detective.
별 노력 없이도 매번
사건을 해결하잖아요
You solve crimes all the time
without even trying.
얼마나 해결했는지 따져 보기도
귀찮을 정도라고요. 왜 이래요!
It's annoying how many crimes
you solve. Come on!
해 봐요. 돈 좀 벌어 보자고요!
Let's go for it.
Let's cash in!
나탈리, 난 돈 때문에 일하진 않아요
Natalie, I don't do what I do for money.
몽크 씨, 100만 달러예요
Mr. Monk, it's a million dollars.
남은 평생을 걱정할 필요가 없다고요
You'll never have to worry
for the rest of your life.
물론 뭐, 그 걱정은 하시겠죠
하지만 돈 걱정은 아니잖아요
Well, of course, you'll worry.
But not about money.
- 모르겠어요
- 몽크 씨, 이 사건을 맡으셔야 해요
- I don't know.
- Mr. Monk, you have to do this.
전 이 일을 좋아하지만
저도 급료는 받아야 하잖아요
I mean, I love this job,
but I have to get paid.
제발, 부탁이에요
Just, just please.
알겠다고 하세요. 하겠다고 해요
대답하세요!
Just say yes. Say you'll do it.
Just say yes!
조리대에서 좀 내려올래요?
Could you get off my counter?
좋아요. 알았어요
하도록 하죠
Okay, fine.
I'll do it.
♪ 100만 달러, 100만 달러 ♪
A million dollars, a million dollars.
축하해요
Congratulations.
실례합니다
용의자가 나왔나요?
Excuse me.
Any suspect yet?
모르겠는데요. 전 그냥
꽃을 배달하러 왔어요
I wouldn't know,
I'm just delivering flowers.
아니, 아니지. 그쪽도
나처럼 사설탐정이잖소
No, you're not. You're
a private detective, just like me.
- 뭐, 꼭 나 같지는 않지만
- 제가 탐정이라고요?
- Well, not quite like me.
- Me, a detective?
정말 재밌네요. 정말로요
That's pretty funny, actually.
저는 얼른 배달하고 돌아가야...
I can't wait to tell the guys back at...
어이, 날 욕보이고 있구먼
자네 차 지붕에 위성 접시가 달렸고
Look, you're insulting me.
That satellite dish on your roof.
옆에 쓰여진 555 번호는
분명 가짜일 게야
The number on the side, 555.
Obviously a fake.
첫 번째 결론, 자넨
알렉산더 다이아몬드를 찾고 있어
Conclusion number one, you're
after the Alexander diamond.
두 번째 결론
자네에겐 희망이 없어
Conclusion number two.
You haven't got a prayer.
잠시만요. 거긴
장애인 주차 구역인데요
Excuse me, that's a handicapped spot.
괜찮아. 난 정신병자거든
It's okay, I'm psychotic.
여기가 그 보석을 도난당한 곳인가요?
Is this where they stole the rock?
- 나한테 말하고 있는 겐가?
- 더 이상은 아니죠
- You addressing me?
- Not anymore.
어이, 범생
여기가 범죄 현장인가?
You, Poindexter.
Is this the scene of the crime?
실례하겠습니다. 저 안에
100만 달러가 절 기다리고 있어서요
Excuse me, boys, I got a million
dollars waiting for me inside.
아, 분명 우린 같은 생각을 하고 있군
Ah, apparently we think alike.
이 신분증 주인들이 알면
기겁할 생각을 말이야
Frightening thought for those
of us who aren't you.
필립 윅, 전 구역 출입이 가능하군
난 이걸로 하겠네
Uh, Phillip Wick.
Access to all areas. This'll do me.
또 만났군
Hello again.
뭐라고 쓰여 있는 거야?
What does this say?
큐레이터 샐리 캔터예요
Curator Sally Kanter.
자, 이걸로 하세요. 로버트 갠트
이건 남자 이름이거든요
Here, try this one, Robert Gant.
That's a boy's name.
어이, 터프가이
우리 모두 목표가 같으니
Uh, look, chaps,
since we're all after the same thing,
- 우리의 재능을 모으는 게 어떤가?
- 무슨 소리 하시는 거예요?
- why don't we just pool our talents?
- What are you talking about?
같이 해결해서 보상금을 쪼개자고
Well, work together and split the reward.
먼저 자기소개부터 시작하지. 어때?
Why don't we begin by
introducing ourselves, all right?
내 이름은 세인트 클레어일세
런던 경찰국 경감이었는데 은퇴했지
My name's st. Clare.
Retired Scotland yard inspector.
- 샌프란시스코로 이사했고...
- 말 좀 끊을게요
- I moved to San Francisco...
- I'm interrupting you.
꿈 깨쇼. 나 혼자
그 보석을 찾아낼 겁니다
No frigging way.
I'm finding that rock myself.
그래서 그 돈을 전부 차지할 거예요
And I'm keeping all the money.
- 그렇다면 최고가 그걸 차지하겠지
- 그게 제가 될 거예요
- Well, may the best man win.
- I intend to.
어린애는 빠져
He said man.
이곳은 옆 동과 차단된 상태였어요
완벽하게 잠겨 있었다는 뜻입니다
This entire wing was locked.
I mean, it was completely locked down.
어떻게 안쪽에서 연결문을 열었는지
Somehow they opened that connecting
door from the inside.
저희도 알아낼 수가 없네요
We can't figure it out.
- 어떻게 생각해요?
- 아직 몰라요
- What do you think?
- I don't know yet.
어서요. 집중해 봐요
할 일을 하시라고요
Well, come on, focus. Concentrate.
Do that thing you do.
- 나탈리가 이러는 건 처음 봐요
- 뭘요? 빈털터리 된 모습요?
- I've never seen you like this.
- What, broke?
- 왜요, 왜요?
- 이곳과 이곳에 흠집이 나 있군요
- What, what, what, what?
- These scratches here and here.
저 타이어 렌치는 이걸 부수기엔
그리 세 보이지 않아요
Looks like these tire irons
weren't heavy enough to do the job.
이봐들, 경쟁 상대가 생겼어
저 사람은 에이드리안 몽크야
Gentlemen, we have competition.
That is Adrian Monk.
에이드리안 몽크요? 저 사람은
살인 사건만 맡는 줄 알았는데요
Adrian monk?
I thought he worked homicide.
둘 다 뭘 그리 걱정해요?
What are you two afraid of?
- 여기 뭔가 이상해요
- 그게 뭔데요?
- Something's off here.
- What is it?
유리 파편이 안쪽에 있잖아요
Glass shards on the inside.
저 보관 유리가 깨졌을 때
When that case was shattered,
이 보관함은 열려 있었어요
this case was open.
범인들이 이 무기를 가져가서
저걸 깬 다음에
I think they took this weapon,
used it,
다시 갖다 놓고 이 보관함을
잠근 것 같아요
and put it back and relocked the case.
- 그걸로 뭘 알 수 있는데요?
- 많죠
- What does that tell us?
- A lot.
바로 내부 소행이었다는 거예요
It means it was an inside job.
그리고 범인들은 내부 소행이라는 걸
들키고 싶지 않았던 거고요
And they didn't want us to know
it was an inside job.
- 땡그렁!
- 그게 무슨 소리예요?
- Ka-ching!
- What does that mean?
돈 떨어지는 소리죠
땡그렁!
It means we're gonna be rich.
Ka-ching.
이 사람 대단한데요
This guy's good.
저 사람이 뭐라고 하는데?
What's he saying?
- 그거 저리 치워
- 무슨 짓이에요?
- Put that thing away.
- What's the problem with you?
잠시만요
Excuse me, sir.
화요일 절도 사건이 일어나기 전에
평소와 다른 점은 없었나요?
Did anything unusual happen
Tuesday before the break-in?
아무거든 보통 때와
달랐던 게 있었나요?
Anything at all out of the ordinary?
그 말을 들으니까 생각나는데요
Now that you mention it,
화요일 오후에 속삭임 소리를
들었, 아니 들은 것 같아요
Tuesday afternoon I heard, or I thought
I heard somebody whispering.
속삭임요?
Whispering?
이 방이 아니고
복도에서 들렸습니다
It wasn't in this room,
it was down the hallway.
2시 30분에 저기쯤
서 있었거든요
It was about 2:30.
I was standing about there.
그때 누가 "내 자궁"(womb)이라고
하는 소리를 들은 것 같아요
And I thought I heard someone
saying, "my womb."
"내 방"(room)요?
"My room"?
"내 자궁"요
남자 목소리였어요
"My womb." It was a man's voice.
- 그리고 그 말을 계속 반복했어요
- "내 자궁"이라...
And he was saying it
over and over. / My womb...
저 통풍구에서 나오는 소리 같았는데
그럴 리가 없죠
I thought it was coming from that vent,
but it's impossible.
아무래도 제가 노망이 드나 봐요
I think I'm going senile.
죄송합니다. 전화 좀 받아야겠네요
여보세요?
I'm sorry, I've got to take this.
Hello?
- 내 자궁
- 내 자궁이라
- My womb.
무슨 묵상할 때 외는 주문 같은데요
It sounds like a mantra like a meditation.
내 자궁(마이 움)...
My womb.
마이 움(oom)-, 마이...
My womb. My...
- 이걸 봐요
- 뭔데요?
- Look at this.
- What?
발자국이에요
It's a footprint.
누가 여기에 숨어 있었던 거예요
Somebody was hiding in here.
여기에요?
Wait, in there?
그래서 저 연결문을
열 수 있었던 거예요
That's how they opened the connecting door.
수사관을 데려와야겠어요
증거 채취 도구가 필요해요
Let's grab the detectives,
we need an evidence kit.
- 잠깐, 아직은 안 돼요
- 무슨 소리예요, 안 된다니?
- Wait, not yet.
- What do you mean, not yet?
다이아몬드부터 찾자고요
그다음에 어떻게 찾았는지 말해 주면 돼요
Let's find the diamond,
then we'll tell them how we did it.
나탈리, 그렇게 장난하듯 하면 안 돼요
Natalie, this is not a game show.
이건 중범죄 수사...
This is a felony investi...
끊어진 목걸이예요
It's a broken necklace.
- 독특한 디자인이군요
- 오, 훌륭해요
- That's an unusual design.
- Oh, good.
이게 뭔지 알아보자고요
어서요. 여기서 나가요
We'll try to ID it.
Come on, let's get out of here.
죄송합니다
Sorry.
괜찮아요?
You okay?
모르겠어요. 뭔가...
뭔가 이상해요
I don't know, something's...
something's wrong.
균형이 잡히질 않네요
I'm not balanced.
어... 잠시만요
Um, excuse me.
그게... 그거 다시 돌려주셨으면 해요
Yeah, um, I'm gonna
be needing that back.
제가 갖고 있는 게 두 개뿐인데
다른 하나는 고장 났거든요
Because I only have two of them
and the other one doesn't work.
- 우릴 따라다니고 있었던 거예요?
- 네?
- Are you following us?
- What?
몽크 씨, 이렇게 영광일 수가 있나
Ah, Mr. Monk. What an honor.
난 세인트 클레어라고 합니다
세인트 클레어 경감이죠
My name's st. Clare.
Inspector st. Clare.
난 대서양 너머에서부터 몽크 씨의
사건들을 죽 따라다니고 있었답니다
I've been following your cases assiduously
from across the pond, you know.
셰익스피어 선생, 누가 신경이나 쓴대요
Shakespeare, nobody cares.
잠깐만요. 우릴 따라다녔다니
믿을 수가 없네요
Wait, I can't believe you're following us.
- 그게 단서인가요?
- 그럴지도요
- Is that a lead?
- Maybe.
저기, 세인트 클레어 경감님
Look, Mr. St. Clare. Inspector.
경감님처럼 점잖으신 분이라면
이 두 개의 단서가 저희 소유라는 걸
I'm sure a gentleman like yourself
can appreciate the fact
- 헤아려 주실 거라고 믿습니다
- 두 개의 단서요?
- that these two leads belong to us.
- Two leads?
네. 목걸이와 저 책상 안에
새겨진 머리글자 말이에요
Well, yes, the necklace and
the initials carved in the desk.
- 몽크 씨!
- 잘못했어요
- Mr. Monk.
- I'm sorry.
어서 가요, 가
Go, go, go, go.
실례합니다
Excuse me.
전 제니 맨더빌이라고 하는데요
My name is Jennie Mandeville.
제가 무슨 짓을 저질러서
자수하러 왔어요
And I did something I'd like to confess.
무슨 일인데요, 제니 씨?
What'd you do, Jennie?
제가 은행을 털었어요
I robbed a bank.
3주 전쯤에요
소살리토에 있는 공동 신탁 금고예요
It was about three weeks ago.
The community savings trust in Sausalito.
소살리토라고요
Sausalito.
- 그런 사건은 들어온 적이 없는데요
- 제가 맡죠
- I don't remember anything about that.
- I'll take it.
안녕하세요, 저는 디셔 경위입니다
제니, 아니, 맨더빌 씨
Hi, I'm lieutenant Disher.
Uh, Jennie. Miss Mandeville.
앉으세요
Just have a seat.
- 뭐 문제 있나요?
- 제가 밀실 공포증이 있거든요
- Uh, is there a problem?
- I'm claustrophobic.
취조실이 여기뿐인가요?
Is this the only room that you have?
방 크기는 다 똑같습니다
앉으세요
All the rooms are the same size, miss.
Please, just have a seat.
난 디셔 경위다. A 취조실에서
제니 맨더빌 씨의 진술을 시작한다
This is lieutenant Disher. I'm in
interrogation room A with Jennie Mandeville.
- 그러니까 은행을 털었단 말이죠
- 맞아요
- So you say you robbed a bank.
- That's right.
은행 안으로 들어갔는데...
I went inside and...
펜 하나를 봤어요
I saw one of those pens.
있잖아요, 탁자에 묶여 있는 거요
You know, chained to the desk?
난 정말 그 펜이 필요했어요
And I really needed a pen.
그래서 그 펜을 확 잡아채서
제 핸드백에 넣어 버렸어요
So I snapped it off
and I put it in my purse.
펜을 훔치셨다고요?
You stole a pen?
펜 한 개요?
One pen?
하나님 맙소사
신께서 절 용서해 주실까요?
Oh, god.
Do you think god will forgive me?
저도 모르겠네요
I don't know, ma'am.
하지만 저희는 용서해 드리죠
그냥 가셔도 좋습니다
But we do.
You're free to go.
아까 그 탐정들은 뭐예요?
우리가 따돌렸을까요?
What is up with those three detectives?
Do you think we lost them?
나탈리, 그 사람들은 탐정이 아니에요
경찰 따라쟁이들일 뿐이죠
Oh, Natalie, they are not detectives.
They're rent-a-cops.
청부업자들이고
현상금 사냥꾼이에요
They're hired guns.
They are mercenaries.
다른 말로, 우리와 같은 부류죠
이 모든 게 탐욕 때문이라고요
In other words, they're us.
This whole thing is about greed.
몽크 씨가 늘 하시는 말씀처럼
나중에 저한테 고맙다고 느끼실걸요
You know how you always say you'll
thank me later? You'll thank me later.
아, 저분일 거예요
Oh, that's gotta be him.
안녕하세요? 콴 씨 맞으세요?
Hello, are you Mr. Kwan?
고개를 끄덕인 것 같은데요
I think he nodded. That...
지금 끄덕이신 거죠?
선생님? 선생님...
was that a nod?
Sir? Sir...
끄덕인 게 맞다면, 또 끄덕여 보세요
If that was a nod, nod.
선생님, 이걸 범죄 현장에서
발견했는데요. 절도 사건이에요
Sir, we found this at the scene
of a crime. A robbery.
몇 가지 여쭤 볼 게 있는데
이거 선생님께서 만드신 거 맞죠?
We've been doing some research.
This is your design, isn't it?
- 학생들에게 이런 걸 주셨나요?
- 나탈리, 잠깐만요
- You give these to your students?
- Natalie, please.
선생님, 실이... 삐져나왔는데요
거기 중간에 매달려 있어요
Sir, you, you have a thread...
hanging right in the middle there.
그냥... 제가 뽑죠
잠시만요...
Just... I'll get it.
Just one moment...
좋아요, 콴 씨. 바쁘신 것 같으니까
요점만 말씀드릴게요
Okay, Mr. Kwan, you look like
a very busy man,
so I'm just gonna get right to the point.
학생들 중에 뚜껑이 달린 책상 속에
들어갈 만한 사람이 있나요?
Do you have a student that
could fit inside of a roll-top desk?
키가 150cm 이상은 안 될 거예요
생각나시나요? 아닌가요?
He can't be more than five feet tall.
Does that ring a bell? Or a gong?
- 몽크 씨, 저분 정신없게 하지 마세요!
- 아니죠. 이분이 날 정신없게 하는 거죠
- Mr. Monk, you're distracting him!
- No, he's distracting me.
여기에 그 정도로 작고
유연한 사람이 있나요?
Is there anyone here
who's that small and limber?
책상 안에 몸을 구겨 넣을 수
있는 사람이 있느냐고요?
Who could scrunch up inside of a desk?
몸집이 작고 몸을 접을 수 있는 사람요?
A scruncher? A little scruncher?
콴 씨, 많은 상금이 걸린
일이라고요 / 해냈어요
Mr. Kwan, there's a lot
of money at stake here. / I got it. I got it.
이런, 이런, 몽크 씨
다시 만났군요
Well, well, well, Mr. Monk.
We meet again.
놀랍죠?
Surprised?
알아서 좀 사건을 해결하시지그래요?
Why don't you get your own clues?
뭐, 보통은 그렇게 합니다만
두 분을 따라다니는 게 너무 쉬워서요
Well, normally I do.
But you two are so easy to follow.
특히 그쪽이 비상 깜빡이를 그렇게
하루 종일 켜놓고 다닐 때는요
Especially when you're kind enough
to keep your emergency blinker on all day long.
- 내가 뭐랬어요
- 안전하게 운전해야죠
- I told you.
- It's the safest way to drive.
잠깐, 아무 말도 묻지 마세요
Wait, don't question anybody yet.
저한테 음성 스트레스
분석기가 있거든요
I have a voice stress analyzer.
저 사람이 거짓말을 하는지
아닌지 분별할 수 있을 거예요
I'll be able to tell
if he's lying or not.
- 저 사람 아무 말도 안 하던데요
- 정말 딱한 애송이로구먼
- He hasn't said anything.
- You are a pathetic little frog, aren't you?
날 떼어냈다고 생각했죠?
모두 좀 쉬도록 하세요
You thought you could lose me, huh?
Well, you can all just relax.
이 더크가 해내도록 하지요
Dirk'll take it from here.
이보쇼, 히피 할아범
Hey, hippie.
당신이 담당자요? 내 이름은 더크요
전문 현상금 사냥꾼이지
You in charge? My name is Dirk.
I'm a professional bounty hunter.
대화 좀 나눴으면 하는데
I was wondering if I could
have a word with you.
이걸 보면 생각이 바뀌시려나?
여기 200달러가 있소 / 200달러요?
Maybe this'll change your mind.
I got $200 here. / $200?
할아범도 돈이 뭔지는 알죠?
They do use money on your planet?
- 14번 숙소예요
- 그런 말 없잖아요
- Cabin 14.
- It doesn't say that.
- 봐요!
- 잘했어요
- Do it!
- You're good.
225달러 드릴게요
$225.
그 학생 이름은 체이슨이야
14번 숙소에 있지
His name is Chasen.
He's over at cabin 14.
어서, 저기에 있다. 어서 가자고!
Come on, there he is. Let's go!
아저씨, 천천히 가요
Hey, slow down.
어서!
Come on!
몽크 씨, 뭐 하는 거예요?
Mr. Monk, what are you doing?
- 도망갈 길이 없다고요!
- 알아냈군요. 몽크 씨!
- No way to go away!
- You got him. Mr. Monk!
돌아와요
Get back here.
실례합니다
Excuse me.
- 실례해요
- 저리 비켜!
- Excuse me.
- Get out of my way!
안녕하세요, 체이슨 씨!
Hello, Mr. Chasen!
이거 댁 목걸이 맞죠?
박물관에서 찾은 거예요
Is this your necklace?
We found it in a museum.
됐어. 다이아몬드는 어디 있지?
Okay, where's the diamond?
이봐! 이봐, 내가 묻고 있잖아
Hey! Hey, I'm talking to you.
이런, 정말 깊은 무아지경에 빠졌군요
Wow, that's a really deep trance.
이보다 더 깊을 순 없겠군
Couldn't be deeper.
이 남자는 죽었어요
This man is dead.
다시 보니 반갑군요, 맨더빌 씨
앉으세요
Welcome back, miss Mandeville.
Have a seat.
어떻게 하는지 아시죠
You know the drill.
전 이 방이 정말 싫어요
I don't like this room.
말씀해 보세요, 맨더빌 씨
Please, miss Mandeville,
긴히 하실 말씀이
있다고 하셨잖아요
you said you had something
important to tell me.
시체에 관한 얘기라고요
Something about a dead body.
그리고 제 사무실에서
말하고 싶지 않다고 하셨죠
And you said you didn't
wanna talk in my office.
말씀드렸잖아요
밀실 공포증이 있다고요
I told you, I'm claustrophobic.
다른 방에서 하면 안 돼요?
What about another room?
안타깝게도 모든 취조실은
크기가 다 똑같답니다
All of our interrogation rooms
are the same size, unfortunately.
전용 바도, 거품 욕조도 없어요
그러니 이제 그만 앉으시죠
No wet bars, no jacuzzis.
Please just have a seat.
자, 시체를 발견했다고 하셨죠
룸메이트의 시체 말이에요
Now, you said you found a body.
Your roommate's body.
이번엔... 진짜 사건 맞겠죠?
This, uh, this is a real thing, right?
그러니까 은행에서 펜을
훔친 그런 거 말고요?
Not like, uh, stealing the pen
from the bank?
자, 좋아요
말씀해 보세요
Okay, good.
Tell me about it.
난 디셔 경위다
This is lieutenant Disher.
D 취조실에서 다시
제니 맨더빌 씨의 진술을 시작한다
I'm in interrogation room D
talking with Jennie Mandeville again.
그럼 처음부터 시작하죠
룸메이트의 이름이 뭐죠?
So let's start from the beginning.
What was your roommate's name?
- 토니요
- 토니요? 성은요?
- Toni.
- Toni? Toni what?
저도 몰라요
I don't know.
모르신다고요?
You don't know.
- 남자입니까, 여자입니까?
- 남자 같아요
- Male or female?
- I think male.
확실히 모르시나요?
You're not sure?
사실대로 말씀드리자면...
To tell you the truth...
바로 요 전날 집에 토니를 데려왔거든요
I just brought him home the day before.
좋아요. 그럼...
계속하죠
Okay. Um...
let's move on.
그러니까 집에 와서
토니를 발견하고는...
So you came home, you found Toni.
직접 시체를 처리하신 건가요?
And you, what, disposed
of the body yourself?
그건 연방법 위반이란 걸 아셔야 합니다
You realize that's a federal offense.
참을 수가 없었다고요. 아셨어요?
I couldn't take it, okay?
그냥 바라보고만 있을 수는 없었어요
I couldn't just stand there looking at it.
제니, 시체를 어떻게 한 건가요?
Jennie, what did you do with the body?
변기에 토니를 씻어 내려 버렸어요
I flushed it down the toilet.
- 토니가 금붕어예요?
- 햄스터요
- Was Toni a goldfish?
- A hamster.
햄스터라고요
A hamster.
좋아요
Okay.
글래디스, 서랍 "속" 청소하는 거
잊지 마세요
Gladys, Don't forget to clean
Inside the drawers.
여기 검시 보고서가 있네
피해자 이름은 대니 체이슨이야
Here's the coroner's report.
Victim's name Danny Chasen.
가명일지도 모르지
피해자는 독살됐네
It's probably an alias.
Victim was poisoned.
누가 피해자의 천연 보리차에
암모니아를 탔어
Somebody spiked his all natural
barley tea with ammonia.
- 이번 절도 사건의 일당이었나요?
- 그런 것 같아
- Was he part of the heist?
- Looks like it.
박물관의 그 뚜껑 달린 책상 안에서
머리카락 몇 개를 발견했는데
They found some hair samples
in that roll-top desk at the museum.
- 피해자와 일치하더군
- 다이아몬드는요?
- They match the body.
- What about the diamond?
아직도 행방불명 상태입니다
피해자한테도 그 숙소에도 없었어요
Still missing in action.
Wasn't on him or in the cabin.
공범자가 있었다는 건 알고 있잖아요
박물관에서 일하는 사람일 거예요
We know he had a partner.
Somebody who works at the museum.
- 아마 아직도 그 사람들이 갖고 있겠죠
- 잠깐, 잠깐만요
- It's probably still with them.
- Wait, wait, wait.
그럼 보상금은 아직 유효한가요?
아무도 청구한 사람이 없는 거죠?
So the reward is still good, right?
I mean, no one's claimed it.
네. 제가 아는 한 그래요
제안은 아직 유효합니다 / 땡그렁!
Yes, as far as I know,
the offer is still good. / Ka-ching.
저 소리 좀 그만 하게 해 주실래요?
Uh, can you make her stop saying that?
이건 이제 단순한
절도 사건이 아니에요
This is no longer a parlor game.
한 남자가 죽었으니
이제 살인 사건이 된 겁니다
A man is dead, this is
a homicide investigation now.
즉, 어떤 정보든 그걸 혼자만
알고 있으면 안 된다는 뜻이에요
Which means nobody is to withhold
any information from anybody.
- 뭐요, 저한테 말씀하시는 거예요?
- 네, 맞아요. 티거 씨
- What, you're looking at me?
- Yes, I am, Ms. Teeger.
당신이 이거 썼죠?
Did you write these?
아니라고 해 봤자 소용없어요
당신인 줄 아니까!
Don't deny it, I know it was you!
"아래 상태는 어때요?
힌트 줄게요, 힌트"
"How are things down under?
Hint, hint."
"몽크 말이 맞았어요
책상 밑면도 청소해야 하겠어요"
"Monk was right, you should
clean under the table."
누굴 속이려고 들어요!
You don't fool me for a second.
"말할 필요도 없지만, 이 포스트잇도
치우는 거 잊지 말아요"라니!
"It goes without saying, don't forget to
throw away these little post-its too."
경감님, 글래디스가 책상
밑면을 청소하지 않는다고요
Captain, she never cleans
under the tables.
- 그쪽이 내 상사는 아니잖아요!
- 내가 상사인 것 같은데요
- You are not the boss of me!
- Well, I think I am the boss of you.
- 왜 그쪽이 상사라고 생각하는데요?
- 내가 상사라면 당신을 해고했을 테니까요!
- What makes you think you're the boss of me?
- If I was the boss of you, you'd be fired!
그만, 이봐요들!
떨어져요. 둘 다
No, hey!
Hey, separate. Both of you.
몽크, 저쪽으로 가
Monk, over there.
글래디스, 잠깐 얘기 좀 할까요?
Gladys, can I have
a word with you, please?
저기요, 글래디스. 몽크잖아요
Look, Gladys, he's Monk.
그냥 무시하도록 해요
Try to ignore him.
경감님이라면 무시할 수 있겠어요?
Can you ignore him?
아뇨, 못하죠
그냥 최선을 다해 보세요
No, I can't.
Just do the best you can.
- 그럼 절 체포하지 않으실 건가요?
- 네. 이번에는요
- So you're not gonna arrest me?
- No, not this time, miss.
하지만, 다음번에 뭔가
자백하고 싶은 느낌이 들면
But listen, the next time
you feel like confessing something,
신부님을 찾아 뵙는 게 좋겠습니다
you might wanna call a priest.
맨더빌 씨를 밖으로 안내해 주겠나?
Will you escort miss Mandeville out?
그러죠
No problem.
- 누구야?
- 이달의 미치광이죠
- Who's she?
- The looney tune of the month.
제니 맨더빌이라고 하는데
Her name's Jennie Mandeville.
계속 여기로 와서
뭔갈 자백한답시고 하네요
She keeps coming in here
and confessing to stuff.
- 이번에는 뭐였는데?
- 어제와 똑같이 굴었습니다
- What was it this time?
- She comes in, same as yesterday.
우연히 자기 룸메이트를 죽였다나요
Says she accidentally
killed her roommate.
그래서 전 취조실로 데려가서
녹음기를 켰죠
So I take her into the back room
and I turn on the tape recorder.
그 룸메이트는 햄스터로 밝혀졌어요
Turns out her roommate was a hamster.
- 불안정한 사람같이 보이진 않던데
- 원래 미친놈들은 다 정상으로 보여
- She didn't look unstable.
- They never do.
자, 이제 일하러 가도 되죠?
없어진 다이아몬드를 찾으러요
Okay, can we get back to work now?
Missing diamond, remember?
땡그렁
Ka-ching.
'땡그렁'이라고요?
나탈리가 저에게 너무 압박을 줍니다
She is putting so much pressure on me.
100만 달러 보상금에 정신이
팔렸습니다. 정신 나갔어요
She's obsessed with this
million-dollar reward. Obsessed.
에이드리안, 나탈리는
돈 걱정을 하고 있는 겁니다
All right, well, Adrian,
she's worried about money.
제가 아는 한, 많은 사람이 그렇죠
Now, I know, a lot of people are.
전 아닙니다
제가 경찰이었을 때는
Not me.
When I was on the force,
월급 수표를 현금으로 바꾸는 것도
싫어했었어요. 지금도 그렇고요
I used to hate cashing my paycheck.
I still do.
저에게 경찰 일은 고귀한 소명과도
같습니다. 성직자처럼요
To me, police work is like a higher calling.
Like the priesthood.
아시다시피 에이드리안
성직자들도 급료는 받아요
You know, Adrian,
even priests have to get paid.
하지만 덕분에 흥미로운
궁금증이 생겼군요
But it brings up an interesting question.
몽크 씨의 정신세계를
들여다볼 수 있는 궁금증이요
Something I would like to explore with you.
만약 100만 달러를 갖고 있다면
뭘 하시겠어요?
What would you do
if you had a million dollars?
그게, 음...
Well, uh...
박사님을 풀타임으로 고용하겠죠
I guess I'd hire you full time.
그리고 언제든 상담이 가능하도록
자문 계약을 하겠어요
And keep you on retainer. 24/7.
제 집 옆에 박사님 집을
사 드릴지도 몰라요
Maybe I'd buy you a house
right next to mine.
언제라도 들를 수 있도록요
So I could just drop in anytime.
이거 재밌군요
박사님은 100만 달러로 뭘 하실래요?
This is fun.
What would you do with a million dollars?
섬을 하나 사겠어요
Buy an island.
무인도를요
A desert island in...
아주 멀리 떨어진 곳이죠
the middle of nowhere.
그러면 상담은
전화로 해야 하겠네요?
So we would do our sessions
over the phone?
제가 생각하고 있는 섬에는...
Well, see, this island, in my mind...
전화가 없습니다
no phone service.
제가 보트를 하나 사야겠군요
I guess I'd have to buy a boat.
그거 재밌군요
제가 꿈꾸고 있는 섬에는...
See, that's funny,
because, the island, in my fantasy...
선착장도 없거든요
no dock.
더 간절한 사람이
이기길 바라야겠네요
Well, may the best man win.
이봐요!
Excuse me!
뭐 하는 짓입니까?
저 사람 봤어요?
What are you doing?
Did you see that?
저 밖에 누군가 있었어요
제가 신고하도록 하지요
There was someone out there.
I'm going to have to report this.
괜찮아요, 괜찮습니다
It's okay. It's okay.
다이아몬드를 찾으려는
다른 탐정일 뿐입니다
He's just another detective
trying to find the diamond.
저런 사람들이 쫙 깔렸어요
There's a whole bunch of them.
어제는 몬터레이에 있는
큰 명상 센터에까지 쫓아왔었죠
Yesterday, they followed us down the coast
to that big meditation center in Monterey.
아, 저도 거기 가 봤어요
아주 아름다운 곳이죠
Oh, I've been there.
It's just beautiful.
하지만, 몇 년 전이었죠
제니 맨더빌이 살아 있을 때니까요
But this was years ago
when Jennie Mandeville was still alive.
- 제니 맨더빌이라고요?
- 제니 맨더빌요
- Jennie Mandeville.
네. 그곳은 제니의 개인 소유지였어요
Yeah, she owned the property.
그곳에 제니의 이름이 새겨진
큰 명판도 있지요
There's this big plaque there
with her name on it.
맞아요
That's right.
기억납니다. 그걸 봤거든요
I remember, I saw it.
왜요?
What?
지금 사건을 해결했어요
I just solved the case.
다이아몬드가 어디에 있는지
알 것 같습니다
I think I know where that diamond is.
가 봐야겠어요
다음 상담 때 20분 더 하죠
I have to go.
We'll add 20 minutes onto my next session.
에이드리안! 에이드리안, 미안하지만
나에게도 방침이 있습니다
Oh, Adrian! Adrian, I'm sorry.
I have a policy.
일찍 떠나신다 해도 전체 상담료를
청구해야 하거든요
If you leave early, I have to
charge you for the whole session.
좋아요
Okay.
좋아요. 자...
좋아요
Okay.
나탈리! 나탈리! 해냈어요!
사건을 해결했다고요!
Natalie! Natalie, I did it!
I solved the case!
- 다이아몬드가 어디 있는지 알겠어요!
- 뭐라고요? 어디에 있는데요?
- I know where the diamond is!
- What? So where is it?
경찰서에 있어요
내내 거기에 있었다고요!
It's at the police station,
it's been there the whole time!
바로 코앞에 있었다니까요
It's been right under our nose.
- 아, 이런
- 누가 내 차에 이런 짓을?
- Oh, my god.
- Who would do that to my car?
오, 맙소사
나탈리! 그 사람들이 듣고 있어요
Oh, my god.
Natalie! They're listening.
네?
What?
그러니까 제 말은
사건을 해결하지 못했다고요
What I meant was,
I didn't solve the case.
그냥 그랬으면 한다는 거죠
완전히 막다른 길이에요
I wish I had, I'm completely stumped.
- 무슨 말을 하시는 거예요?
- 아뇨, 기다려 봐요
- What are you talking about?
- No, wait.
솔직히 제 말은
사건을 해결했다는 거예요
What I really meant was,
I did solve the case.
다이아몬드는 필리핀에 있어요
The diamond is in the Philippines.
공항으로 가야겠어요
필리핀으로 날아가서...
We gotta go the airport,
fly to the...
그만 하고 어서 달려요!
달리라고요!
Forget about it.
Just run! Run!
몽크! 몽크 씨!
Monk! Mr. Monk!
- 몽크 씨!
- 이런
- Mr. Monk!
- My god.
이봐요!
Hey!
내 말 좀 들어 봐요!
Talking to you!
몽크, 몽크 씨! 이리 와요!
얘기 좀 하자고요, 친구
Monk, Mr. Monk! Come on!
Talk, little friend.
여기, 여기예요!
Here, here, here!
가운데 골목으로 갔어요!
Through the middle alley!
말했잖아요, 몽크 씨!
I said, Mr. Monk!
천천히 가요!
Slow down!
어이, 멈추라고!
Hey, stop!
오, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
Oh, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
1, 2, 3, 4...
- 제발 좀 멈춰요
- 멈춰, 이 얼간아!
- Please, stop.
- Change, you, schmuck!
비켜!
Get out of the way!
- 봤어?
- 놓쳤어요
- Did you see them?
- We lost them.
잠깐만요
Wait.
우린 몽크를 따라다녔고
몽크를 관찰하고 다녔어요
We've been following Monk,
we've been watching Monk.
그런데 왜 몽크처럼
생각해 보려 하지 않는 거죠?
Why don't we try thinking like monk?
몽크처럼 생각해... 몽크처럼 생각해
몽크처럼 생각해
Think like Monk. Think like Monk.
Think like Monk.
몽크처럼 생각해
- 뭐 하시는 거예요?
- 몽크는 저쪽으로 갔어
- What are you doing?
- He went that way.
따돌린 것 같아요
I think we lost them.
계속 그렇게 말하고 있지만
절대 그럴 리가 없어요
You keep saying that,
but we never do.
여기, 여기요
택시! 택시!
Hey, hey, hey.
Taxi! Taxi!
빈톤 가에 있는 경찰 본부로 가 주세요
Police headquarters on Vinton street.
- 뭐 하는 거예요?
- 저분과 동행입니다
- What are you doing, chief?
- I'm with her.
뒤쪽에 타셔야죠
규정대로 하세요
You gotta ride in the back,
that's the rule.
앞쪽에 앉는 걸 좋아해서요
내 규정 중 하나입니다
No, I prefer to sit up front.
It's one of my things.
사실이에요. 이분 규정 중 하나죠
It's true, it's one of his things.
내 규정을 알려 드리지
누구도 앞에는 탈 수 없어요
Well, here's one of my things.
Nobody rides in the front.
- 미안하지만 협상할 수 없군요
- 누가 협상하겠대요?
- I'm afraid it's not negotiable.
- Who's negotiating?
- 됐어요. 난 가겠습니다
- 워, 워, 워, 잠깐, 잠깐만요!
- That's it, I'm out of here.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait, wait!
앞쪽에 타게 해 주신다면
50달러를 드릴게요
I'll give you 50 bucks
if you let him ride up front.
- 왜요? 무슨 꿍꿍이죠?
- 아무것도, 아무것도요
- Why? What's he gonna do?
- Nothing, nothing.
여러 가지 강박증과 공포증 때문에
He's got a cluster of
compulsions and phobias
이런저런 규정에
얽매이는 것뿐이에요
that manifest themselves
in a variety of, you know...
지금도 그것 때문에 그러는 거예요
규정이 있다니까요 / 100달러 내쇼
it's one of his things.
He has things. / $100.
좋아요, 72달러
그게 가진 것 전부예요
All right, 72.
That's all I have.
- 어서 타세요
- 잠깐, 잠깐만요
- Welcome aboard.
- Whoa, whoa, wait.
이 점검 스티커는
기한이 어제까지인데요
This inspection sticker expired yesterday.
- 그래요. 내일 점검 받을 겁니다
- 기한이 만료됐어요. 만료됐다고요
- Yeah, I'm taking care of that tomorrow.
- Expired. It's expired.
몽크 씨, 100만 달러라니까요
절 위해서라도 택시에 좀 타세요
Mr. Monk, it's a million dollars.
Please get in the cab for me.
기한이 만료됐어요
It's expired.
됐어요. 관둬요
내 돈 다시 줘요
Forget about it, forget about it.
Give me back my money.
환불은 안 돼요
이것도 내 규정 중 하나랍니다
No refunds.
It's one of my things.
몽크!
이봐요, 몽크 씨! 몽크 씨!
Monk!
Hey, Mr. Monk, Mr. Monk!
우리... 우리 친하게
지내면 안 될까요?
Can we, uh, can we be soft
chumming up here?
몽크!
Monk!
어디에...
Where's...
where's...
- 아, 디셔요
- 네, 맞아요
- Oh, Disher.
- Yeah, yeah.
관찰실에 있는 것 같은데요
I think he's in the observation room.
글래디스, 우리 쫓기고 있거든요
우릴 봤다고 말씀하시면 안 돼요
Gladys, we're being followed.
Don't tell anybody you saw us.
- 문을 잠갔어!
- "미시오"라고 쓰여 있잖아 / 비켜요!
- They locked the door!
- It says "push." / Get out of the way!
저쪽으로 갔어요
That way.
경위! 경위! 자네가 체포한
그 경비원 기억하지? / 네
Lieutenant! Lieutenant, remember the
security guard that you arrested? / Yeah.
- 어디서 취조했어?
- 저기요. B 취조실요
- Where did you interrogate him?
- Right there, room B.
그 계속 자백만 하던
제니 맨더빌 말인데
And the girl who kept confessing,
Jennie Mandeville,
- 어디서 취조했지?
- A 취조실과 D 취조실요
- where did you take her?
- Room A then room D.
- 그럼 저기에서는 안 했어?
- 네, 안 했어요
- But she was never in there?
- No, no.
그럼 아직 저기에 있을 거야
저 방이라고!
It's gotta still be in there.
In that room!
저기에 뭐가 있는데?
몽크, 무슨 일이야?
What's in there?
Monk, what's going on?
나중에 말씀드릴게요 / 워, 잠깐만요
여기에 들어오시면 안 됩니다
Tell you later. / Whoa, whoa, whoa,
you cannot come in here.
내 친구인 이 두 사람은 미국 시민이오
여기 들어올 권리가 있다고!
My two friends are American citizens.
They have a right to be here.
내겐 임시 비자가 있고요
Myself, I am on a temporary visa.
- 연장해야 하지만
- 자네 동료들이야?
- Which I hope to extend.
- Are they with you?
굳이 아주 굉장히 엄밀히 따지자면요
Only in the strictest,
most terrible sense of the word.
정신과 의사에게 사건을
해결했다고 하는 말을 들었어요
I heard you tell your shrink
you solved the case.
실례해요
Excuse me.
아무도 여기에서 못 나가!
Nobody's going anywhere.
저 사람이 아는 걸 우리가
알 때까지는 안 돼
Not until we know what he knows.
자네 큰 실수하는 거야
공교롭게도 난 경감이거든
You just made a big mistake, my friend.
I happen to be a police captain.
그리고 이건 불법 감금일세
체포해
And this is an unlawful imprisonment.
Book him.
당신을 체포합니다. 돌아서세요
You're under arrest. Turn around.
좋아요. 손을 내미세요
Fine, give me your hands.
- 수갑 갖고 계세요?
- 내 사무실에 있어
- Do you have your cuffs?
- In my office.
저기에 있죠. 그렇죠?
It's in there, isn't it?
다이아몬드는 바로 저 방에 있어
The diamond is in that very room.
- 뭐라고요?
- 그래?
- What?
- It is?
조용히 해요!
모두 조용히 하라고!
Shut up!
Everybody, shut up!
몽크만 빼고 조용히 해요
Everybody but Monk.
- 몽크, 어떻게 된 거야?
- 알았어요
- Monk, what's going on?
- Okay.
이렇게 된 거예요
Here's what happened.
제니 맨더빌이란 여자는 바로
그 명상 센터를 건립한 사람이에요
The woman who founded the meditation center
was named Jennie Mandeville.
- 그 자백한 여자요?
- 아니, 아니, 아니라니까
- What, the confessor?
- No, no, no, no.
자네가 만난 그 여자는
진짜 제니 맨더빌이 아니었어
The girl you met was
not the real Jennie Mandeville.
명상 센터의 명판을 보고
그 이름을 사용한 거야
She got the name from a plaque
she saw up at the retreat.
가짜 이름이 필요하던 차에
그 이름이 맘에 들었던 거겠지
She needed a fake name,
maybe she liked the sound of it.
- 그 여자가 거긴 뭐 하러 간 건데?
- 대니 체이슨을 살해하러 간 겁니다
- What was she doing up there?
- She went there to kill Danny Chasen.
그 뚜껑 달린 책상 속에 있던 남자요
The guy in the roll-top desk.
아마 그 여자 남자 친구의
아이디어였을 거예요
It was probably her boyfriend's idea.
보석 절도범들은 어린아이 같아서
서로 나누는 걸 싫어하죠
Jewel thieves are like children.
They hate to share.
방이 아주 혼잡하군요
This is a very crowded room.
아주, 아주, 아주, 아주...
This is a very, very, very, very,
very, very...
몽크, 이봐, 몽크. 괜찮아
괜찮다고
Monk, Monk, Monk, it's okay.
It's okay.
- 남자 친구가 누구야?
- 랜디가 체포한 그 경비원요
Who was her boyfriend? / He was
the security guard that Randy arrested.
그 남자가 보석 도둑이었어요!
내부 사람이었잖아요
He was the jewel thief!
He was the inside man.
자네가 그 남자와 얘기할 때에도
다이아몬드는 그 남자 주머니에 있었어
The diamond was still in his pocket
when you were talking to him.
맞아요. 박물관에서 그 남자를
여기로 바로 데려왔었죠
That's right, we brought him here
right from the museum.
내 기억으로 그 사람은 취조 전에
입 안 가득 껌을 씹고 있었어
I remember before the interrogation
he was chewing a big piece of gum.
그런데 취조실에서 나왔을 땐
그 껌은 없었다고
But when I saw him after the interrogation,
the gum was gone.
그 사람은 취조실에서
어찌할 줄 몰라 했을 거야
He must be panicked in that room.
마약 제조 혐의가 있었고
체포될 거란 걸 알았으니까 말이야
You had him on the drug charges,
he knew he was about to be arrested.
즉, 자기 몸이 수색당할 거란 뜻이었지
Which, of course, meant he'd be searched.
그래서 그 보석을
책상 밑에 숨긴 거야
So he hid the rock right there
under the table.
껌에 붙여서 말이지
With his chewing gum.
레스토랑에서도
항상 사람들이 그러잖아요
People do it in restaurants all the time.
국회와 신문사에 편지만 계속 보내고 있죠
제가 달리 어쩔 수 있겠어요?
I've written letters to my congressman
and to the editor. What can I do?
그 남자가 감옥에서
여자 친구에게 전화를 걸어
He must have telephoned
his girlfriend from jail
어디에 다이아몬드를
숨겼는지 말한 게 분명해요
to tell her where he stashed the diamond.
그래서 그 여자가 자백을
한답시고 여기에 왔던 거군
And that's why she was coming in here
confessing to everything.
그래서 자꾸 방을
바꾸자고 했던 거고요
And why she was always
asking to switch rooms,
- 저 방에 들어가야만 했었으니까요
- 됐어요, 그만 해요. 맘을 바꿨어요
- 'cause she was trying to get in there.
- All right, okay. I changed my mind.
여기 7명이 있고, 우린 모두 성인이니
보상금을 7등분으로 나눕시다
There's seven of us and we're all adults.
We'll just divide the money seven ways.
말도 안 돼요
우리가 맨 처음 여기에 왔다고요
No way.
We were here first.
보상금을 나누는 게 가장
공평하다고 생각되는군요
I think it's only fair
that we divide the proceeds.
서로 협력해서 수사해 왔으니까요
I mean, we have been working in tandem.
무슨 협력을 해요. 댁들이
쫓아다닌 거죠. 그건 협력이 아니라고요
We've not been working in tandem.
You've been chasing us. That's not tandem.
실례지만, 한 가지만 말씀드려도 될까요?
Excuse me, could I say one thing?
당신, 나탈리 그리고 클레어 씨가
내 공기로 숨을 쉬고 있어요
You and you and you...
you're breathing my air.
저 사람들은요? / 자네 공기를 쉬고 있지
자네는 클레어 씨의 공기를 쉬고 있고
What about them? / They're breathing
your air. You're breathing his.
복잡하긴 하지만 만약
이 두 사람이 뒤로 물러난다면...
It's complicated.
But if these two dropped back...
몽크, 몽크, 괜찮아
내가 도움을 청해 볼게
Monk, Monk, it's okay.
I'll call for help.
알았어요
Okay.
맙소사, 글래디스예요
Oh, my god. Gladys.
안 돼, 안 돼, 안 돼, 안 돼
멈춰요, 멈추라고요
No, no, no, no.
Stop, stop.
몽크 씨?
Monk?
당신이에요?
Is that you?
날 내버려 두라고 말했을 텐데요
I told you to leave me alone.
누가 화장실에서 토했대요!
Somebody barfed in the bathroom!
안 돼, 안 된다고요!
No, come on!
안 돼요!
Hey!
그만, 됐어요! 봐요
Okay, fine! Look,
원하시는 대로 책상 밑면을
청소해 드리도록 하죠. 됐죠?
I'm gonna clean under the table
just like you want, okay?
그냥 둬요!
책상은 그냥 두고 청소하시라고요!
Go over!
Go over the table and clean!
- 책상은 놔두고 청소하라니까요!
- 어때요? 이제 행복해요?
- Go over the table and clean!
- Okay? You happy?
못 보겠어
I can't look.
땡-그렁!
Ka-ching.
저 여자가 어젯밤 늦게 다시 와서는
뭔가 자백할 게 있다고 하더군
She came in again late last night.
Said she had something to confess to.
- 이번엔 진짜 자백을 하게 됐지
- 자, 이거 들어보세요
- This time we got a real confession.
- Okay, listen to this.
"지난 22년간 청소 용역 업체에서
일했던 글래디스 윈침 씨는"
"Gladys Winchim, who was employed by
a local cleaning service for the last 22 years,"
"보상금을 받기 위해 개인 전용기로
런던으로 가게 될 것이다"
"will be flown to London on a private jet
to pick up her reward."
"윈침 씨는 취조실에 있는 책상 밑면을
청소하면서 도난당한 보석을 발견했다"
"Miss Winchim found the stolen gem
while cleaning under a table
in an interrogation room."
- 날 나무라는 거예요?
- 책상 밑면이라니!
- Are you blaming me?
- Under a table!
왜 사람들은 다시 껌을 가져가지
않을까요? 온통 껌 천지라니까요
Why do they even want it back?
there's gum all over it.
좋은 소식이 있어
뭐 일종의 애석상이라고 봐야겠지
I've got some good news,
sort of consolation prize.
국장님과 얘기해 봤는데
I talk to the commissioner.
- 자네랑 계약을 하겠다고 하시더군
- 정말요?
- He's gonna put you under contract.
- Really?
자문으로 임명하겠대
Put you on retainer.
앞으로 2년 동안 연간 16건의
살인 사건을 맡기시겠다더군
He has guaranteed you 16 homicides
a year for next two years.
1년에 16건이라...
그럼 계약이 끝나면요?
16 a year. What, what happen,
what about after that?
뭐...
1년씩 갱신하도록 하지
Well...
let's take one year at a time.
괜찮을 거야
We'll see.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)